=Within The Grip=
=ภายในด้ามจับ=
=Episode 2=
= ตอนที่ 2=
(Chaosheng Comes Late at Night)
(Chaosheng มาตอนดึก)
(Zhanchun Pavilion, Gu Mansion)
(ศาลา Zhanchun, คฤหาสน์ Gu)
Master.
ผู้เชี่ยวชาญ.
(Gu Jiang, head of the Gu family)
(กู่เจียง หัวหน้าตระกูลกู่)
(Heaven)
(สวรรค์)
(During this period, I disguised myself and investigated beside General Shen.)
(ช่วงนี้ผมปลอมตัว. และสอบสวนร่วมกับนายพล Shen)
(He didn't commit treason.)
(เขาไม่ได้ก่อกบฏ)
(He's an upright and incorruptible man.)
(เขาเป็นคนเที่ยงตรงและไม่เสื่อมสลาย)
(He already caught the one who framed him in Suzhou.)
(เขาจับได้แล้ว. ที่ใส่ร้ายเขาในซูโจว)
(He will return soon.)
(เขาจะกลับมาเร็วๆ นี้)
You've done well.
คุณทำได้ดีแล้ว
Since General Shen is not involved in that matter,
ตั้งแต่นายพลเซิน ไม่เกี่ยวข้องกับเรื่องนั้น
his name is cleared.
ชื่อของเขาชัดเจนแล้ว
I promised
ฉันสัญญา
to hand Xuanji Pavilion over to you after your marriage to Zhaoxi.
เพื่อมอบศาลาซวนจีให้กับคุณ หลังจากคุณแต่งงานกับ Zhaoxi
Now, he...
ตอนนี้เขา...
Heaven will protect Master Zhaoxi.
สวรรค์จะปกป้องอาจารย์จ้าวซี
I heard about the thing a few days ago.
ฉันได้ยินเรื่องนี้เมื่อไม่กี่วันก่อน
I've already made Chaosheng accept his punishment.
ฉันได้สร้าง Chaosheng แล้ว ยอมรับการลงโทษของเขา
I'm sorry about that.
ฉันขอโทษเกี่ยวกับเรื่องนั้น
I'll await Master Zhaoxi's safe return.
ฉันจะรอการกลับมาอย่างปลอดภัยของอาจารย์จ้าวซี
(Heaven) Go and report back.
(สวรรค์) ไปรายงานกลับด้วย
Yes.
ใช่.
(Xuanji Pavilion)
(ศาลาซวนจี)
(19 years ago, Gu Jiang went mad during a visit.)
(19 ปีที่แล้ว กู่เจียง โกรธมากระหว่างการเยี่ยมชม)
(He killed the family of Left Chancellor Qin Yuheng.)
(เขาฆ่าครอบครัว ของนายกรัฐมนตรีฝ่ายซ้าย ฉิน ยูเหิง)
(This Heaven mission remains unresolved in the Shadow Pavilion.)
(ภารกิจสวรรค์นี้ยังคงอยู่ ไม่ได้รับการแก้ไขใน Shadow Pavilion)
(Gu Jiang brought back Qin Yuheng's baby daughter, Qin Xiang,)
(กู่เจียงนำกลับมา ฉินเซียง ลูกสาวตัวน้อยของฉิน ยูเหิง)
(kept her in Xuanji Pavilion)
(เก็บเธอไว้ที่ศาลาซวนจี๋)
(and named her Yuluo.)
(และตั้งชื่อเธอว่า หยูลัว)
(Xuan Wu, Xuan Unit of Xuanji Pavilion)
(ซวนวู หน่วยซวนของศาลาซวนจี)
I thought I'd be congratulating the new Pavilion Master.
ฉันคิดว่าฉันจะแสดงความยินดี พาวิเลียนมาสเตอร์คนใหม่
Sorry to disappoint you.
ขออภัยที่ทำให้คุณผิดหวัง
I didn't expect you to be interested in the position of Pavilion Master.
ฉันไม่ได้หวังให้คุณสนใจ ในตำแหน่งเจ้าอาวาส.
(Earth)
(โลก)
(Xuanji Pavilion)
(ศาลาซวนจี)
Don't worry. I'm not that impatient.
ไม่ต้องกังวล. ฉันไม่ได้ใจร้อนขนาดนั้น
I'm waiting for your action.
ฉันกำลังรอการกระทำของคุณ
What do you truly want, Master?
คุณต้องการอะไรจริงๆครับอาจารย์?
I dare not guess your mind.
ฉันไม่กล้าคาดเดาความคิดของคุณ
But over all these years,
แต่ตลอดหลายปีที่ผ่านมา
you've never wanted for anything.
คุณไม่เคยต้องการสิ่งใดเลย
Why this obsession now?
ทำไมตอนนี้ถึงหลงใหลเรื่องนี้?
The secret scrolls within the pavilion are only accessible to Pavilion Masters.
คัมภีร์ลับภายในศาลา เข้าถึงได้เฉพาะ Pavilion Masters เท่านั้น
Does your desire to become the Xuanji Pavilion Master
ความปรารถนาของคุณที่จะเป็น ปรมาจารย์ศาลาซวนจี
have something to do with the anonymous letter you often read?
มีบางอย่างเกี่ยวข้องกับ จดหมายนิรนามที่คุณอ่านบ่อยๆ?
(The contents of that secret letter)
(เนื้อหาของจดหมายลับนั้น)
(are connected to Xuanji Pavilion's Heaven mission.)
(มีการเชื่อมต่อ สู่ภารกิจสวรรค์ของศาลาซวนจี)
(To know if the thing back then is true,)
(ถ้าจะรู้ว่าสิ่งนั้น. ย้อนกลับไปเป็นเรื่องจริง)
(I need to wait.)
(ต้องรอก่อน)
I'd like to share your burdens, Master.
ฉันอยากจะแบ่งปันภาระของคุณอาจารย์
You've already shared many.
คุณได้แบ่งปันหลายรายการแล้ว
(Fufeng Pavilion, Gu Mansion)
(ศาลา Fufeng, คฤหาสน์ Gu)
Do you recognize what these are?
คุณรู้ไหมว่าสิ่งเหล่านี้คืออะไร?
How would I recognize these women's stuff?
ฉันจะรับรู้ได้อย่างไร ของผู้หญิงพวกนี้เหรอ?
Actually, you'll need all of them.
ที่จริงแล้วคุณจะต้องมีทั้งหมด
I have repaid the money you owed
ฉันได้ชำระเงินที่คุณเป็นหนี้แล้ว
at Zuixian Building.
ณ อาคารซุยเซียน
I've also sent people to find your relatives in the city.
ฉันยังส่งคนไป เพื่อไปหาญาติของคุณในเมือง
In your name, I gifted them 100 taels of gold and arranged careful protection.
ในนามของคุณ ฉันมอบเงินให้พวกเขา 100 ตำลึง ทองคำและได้จัดเตรียมความคุ้มครองไว้อย่างดี
Do you have any other wishes?
คุณมีความปรารถนาอื่นอีกไหม?
He wouldn't look at me the way you do.
เขาคงไม่มองฉันแบบที่คุณมอง
How would he look?
เขาจะดูเป็นอย่างไร?
This is Master Zhaoxi.
นี่คืออาจารย์จ้าวซี
(Gu Zhaoxi, third young master of the Gu family)
(กู่จ้าวซี นายน้อยคนที่สาม ของตระกูลกู่)
♪Slowly turning into love♪
♪ค่อยๆ กลายเป็นความรัก♪
♪But why is there a sigh in your eyes♪
♪แต่ทำไมคุณถึงถอนหายใจล่ะ♪
♪Flowers bloom and you'll return♪
♪ดอกไม้บานแล้วคุณจะกลับมา♪
♪We're bound to meet♪
♪เราจะต้องได้พบกัน♪
♪My heart has never been far away♪
♪ใจฉันไม่เคยห่างไกล♪
Lady, feel free.
คุณหญิง สบายใจได้
Though we've lived in the same mansion, we've never met.
แม้ว่าเราจะมีชีวิตอยู่ ในคฤหาสน์หลังเดียวกันเราไม่เคยพบกัน
I have long heard of you.
ฉันได้ยินเรื่องของคุณมานานแล้ว
Regarding our marriage,
เกี่ยวกับการแต่งงานของเรา
since Father has arranged it, there must be a reason.
เพราะหลวงพ่อได้จัดไว้แล้ว ต้องมีเหตุผล
But I'm frail and chronically ill.
แต่ฉันอ่อนแอและป่วยเรื้อรัง
If you are unwilling, I will persuade Father
หากคุณไม่เต็มใจ ฉันจะชักชวนพ่อ
to decline this marriage.
ที่จะปฏิเสธการแต่งงานครั้งนี้
♪Stroke by stroke, bit by bit♪
♪ทีละจังหวะ ทีละนิด♪
♪Like rain seeping into the earth♪
♪เหมือนฝนที่ไหลซึมสู่ดิน♪
♪Love blooms from the void♪
♪ความรักเบ่งบานจากความว่างเปล่า♪
♪I'll accompany you to whatever end♪
♪ฉันจะตามคุณไปไม่ว่าจุดจบจะเป็นอย่างไร♪
♪Helplessly falling for you♪
♪ตกหลุมรักคุณอย่างช่วยไม่ได้♪
♪You are my only one♪
♪เธอคือคนเดียวของฉันเท่านั้น♪
♪Writing a love poem for you♪
♪เขียนกลอนรักเพื่อคุณ♪
♪Writing our unfinished story♪
♪กำลังเขียนเรื่องราวที่ยังไม่เสร็จของเรา♪
♪Your name fills every line♪
♪ ชื่อของคุณเต็มทุกบรรทัด ♪
♪Let time rush by♪
♪ปล่อยให้เวลาผ่านไปอย่างรวดเร็ว♪
♪Love so deep, I care not for the cost♪
♪รักลึกซึ้ง ไม่สนใจต้นทุน♪
♪This moment weaves eternity♪
♪ช่วงเวลานี้สานต่อความเป็นนิรันดร์♪
Master, we should leave.
อาจารย์ เราควรออกไปแล้ว
♪Writing our unfinished story♪
♪กำลังเขียนเรื่องราวที่ยังไม่เสร็จของเรา♪
♪Countless stars reflect your face♪
♪ดวงดาวนับไม่ถ้วนสะท้อนใบหน้าของคุณ♪
♪Let time rush by♪
♪ปล่อยให้เวลาผ่านไปอย่างรวดเร็ว♪
♪Love so deep, I care not for the cost♪
♪รักลึกซึ้ง ไม่สนใจต้นทุน♪
Master Zhaoxi,
อาจารย์จ้าวซี
I'm willing.
ฉันเต็มใจ.
♪A love poem awaits our rediscovery♪
♪บทกวีรักกำลังรอการค้นพบของเราอีกครั้ง♪
When you fully recover,
เมื่อคุณฟื้นตัวเต็มที่
we can finish this game together.
เราจะจบเกมนี้ด้วยกันได้
I shall await your return.
ฉันจะรอการกลับมาของคุณ
(He must not find out that Gu Zhaoxi and I have only met once.)
(เขาจะต้องไม่พบว่า Gu Zhaoxi นั้น และเคยพบกันเพียงครั้งเดียว)
My husband is the gentlest, most humble, and kindest man in the world to me.
สามีของฉันเป็นคนอ่อนโยนและถ่อมตัวที่สุด และเป็นผู้ชายที่ใจดีที่สุดในโลกสำหรับฉัน
He indulges me in everything.
เขาตามใจฉันในทุกสิ่ง
Whether I want frost flowers atop the mountain
ไม่ว่าฉันต้องการดอกไม้น้ำค้างแข็ง บนยอดเขา
or fireflies on a summer night,
หรือหิ่งห้อยในคืนฤดูร้อน
he would seek them out for me.
เขาจะตามหาพวกเขาให้ฉัน
If I get up early, he prepares congee for me.
ถ้าฉันตื่นเช้า เขาเตรียมโจ๊กให้ฉัน
If I return late, he lights a lamp and waits for me.
ถ้าฉันกลับมาช้า เขาจุดตะเกียงและรอฉันอยู่
We share perfect harmony and play chess in our leisure.
เราแบ่งปันความสามัคคีที่สมบูรณ์แบบ และเล่นหมากรุกในยามว่างของเรา
Knowing I fear the cold, he often warms my hands with his.
รู้ว่ากลัวความหนาว เขามักจะอุ่นมือของฉันด้วยมือของเขา
He's delighted whenever he sees me.
เขาดีใจทุกครั้งที่เห็นฉัน
When he smiles,
เมื่อเขายิ้ม
it's like a clear breeze and bright moon, pure and untainted.
มันเหมือนสายลมที่ชัดเจน และพระจันทร์อันสุกใสบริสุทธิ์ไร้มลทิน
From now on, you are my husband, Gu Zhaoxi.
ตั้งแต่บัดนี้เป็นต้นไป คุณคือสามีของฉัน Gu Zhaoxi
(Can two people truly be so identical in this world?)
(คนสองคนเป็นได้จริงๆ. เหมือนกันมากในโลกนี้?)
(Or...)
(หรือ...)
The Gu family specializes in disguise.
ครอบครัว Gu เชี่ยวชาญในการปลอมตัว
They replaced your coachman and tried to assassinate you.
พวกเขาเข้ามาแทนที่โค้ชของคุณ และพยายามจะลอบสังหารคุณ
They even created a face identical to yours at their place.
พวกเขายังสร้างใบหน้าอีกด้วย เหมือนกับของคุณ ณ ที่ของพวกเขา
I wonder what they are plotting.
ฉันสงสัยว่าพวกเขากำลังวางแผนอะไร
Investigate them,
ตรวจสอบพวกเขา
and then we'll know.
แล้วเราจะได้รู้
I will briefly tell you some of his habits and preferences.
ผมจะเล่าสั้นๆให้ฟังบ้าง ถึงนิสัยและความชอบของเขา
Tomorrow, we can announce the news of your return.
พรุ่งนี้ประกาศได้เลย ข่าวการกลับมาของคุณ
Your voice is a problem.
เสียงของคุณมีปัญหา
However,
อย่างไรก็ตาม
we can use your injury as an excuse
เราสามารถใช้อาการบาดเจ็บของคุณเป็นข้อแก้ตัว
to avoid guests while you adapt.
เพื่อหลีกเลี่ยงแขกในขณะที่คุณปรับตัว
As for the sword wound on your body,
ส่วนบาดแผลของดาบบนตัวคุณ
it can also serve as the reason for your delayed return.
มันสามารถใช้เป็นเหตุผลได้เช่นกัน สำหรับการกลับมาล่าช้าของคุณ
Let me see your sword wound.
ขอฉันดูบาดแผลดาบของคุณหน่อยสิ
A minor injury.
อาการบาดเจ็บเล็กน้อย
It's already been dressed.
มันแต่งตัวเรียบร้อยแล้ว
You're so easily flustered.
คุณสับสนง่ายมาก
How will you handle pretending to be my husband?
คุณจะรับมืออย่างไร แกล้งทำเป็นสามีของฉันเหรอ?
Master Chaosheng, my master is bathing. You cannot enter.
อาจารย์เฉาเฉิง อาจารย์ของข้าพเจ้า กำลังอาบน้ำ คุณไม่สามารถเข้าได้
What? A Xuanji Pavilion's death guard is fighting against me?
อะไร ผู้คุมความตายของศาลาซวนจี กำลังต่อสู้กับฉันเหรอ?
Such deep affection between you two.
ความรักอันลึกซึ้งระหว่างคุณทั้งสอง
It makes me look like the villain,
มันทำให้ฉันดูเหมือนตัวร้าย
breaking up you couple and ruining our brotherhood.
เลิกกันคู่รักของคุณ และทำลายความเป็นพี่น้องของเรา
You have your reasons.
คุณมีเหตุผลของคุณ
But Zhaoxi and I vowed to be together long ago.
แต่ฉันกับจ้าวซีสาบานไว้ ที่จะอยู่ด้วยกันนานมาแล้ว
So I refuse to believe he would abandon me.
ฉันจึงปฏิเสธที่จะเชื่อ เขาจะทิ้งฉัน
I have heard something interesting.
ฉันเคยได้ยินสิ่งที่น่าสนใจ
My martial-obsessed fourth brother, who once studied at the Xuanji Pavilion,
พี่ชายคนที่สี่ที่หมกมุ่นอยู่กับการต่อสู้ของฉัน ผู้เคยศึกษาอยู่ที่ศาลาซวนจี
seems quite close to you as well.
ดูเหมือนจะค่อนข้างใกล้กับคุณเช่นกัน
What do you mean by that?
คุณหมายถึงอะไรโดยที่?
Although we both come from the Xuanji Pavilion,
แม้ว่าเราทั้งสองจะมา จากศาลาซวนจี
we merely have a master-servant bond.
เราเพียงมีความผูกพันระหว่างนายกับบ่าวเท่านั้น
How can you say we are close?
ไหนบอกว่าเราสนิทกันไง?
Master and servant?
เจ้านายและคนรับใช้?
So you know your place?
แล้วคุณรู้จักสถานที่ของคุณไหม?
But I heard
แต่ฉันได้ยิน
he wrote to Father requesting to marry you?
เขาเขียนถึงพ่อ ขอแต่งงานกับคุณเหรอ?
I think you wouldn't believe such baseless rumors.
ฉันคิดว่าคุณคงไม่เชื่อ ข่าวลือที่ไม่มีมูลความจริงเช่นนั้น
The dead Zhaoxi and the martial-obsessed fourth brother.
จ้าวซีผู้ตาย และน้องชายคนที่สี่ที่หมกมุ่นอยู่กับการต่อสู้
Instead of focusing your efforts on them,
แทนที่จะเน้น. ความพยายามของคุณกับพวกเขา
if you want the Xuanji Pavilion
หากคุณต้องการศาลา Xuanji
or to become master of the Gu family,
หรือจะเป็นเจ้านายของตระกูล Gu
curry favor with me.
โปรดเมตตาฉันด้วย
Who's there?
มีใครอยู่บ้าง?
Just the wind.
แค่ลม..
What are you worried about? Eavesdroppers?
คุณกังวลเรื่องอะไร? คนดักฟัง?
Worried?
กังวล?
I only worry your loyalty to Zhaoxi isn't as unwavering as you claim.
ฉันแค่กังวลถึงความภักดีของคุณต่อ Zhaoxi ไม่ได้มั่นคงอย่างที่คุณอ้าง
Hiding a man in your room?
ซ่อนผู้ชายไว้ในห้องของคุณเหรอ?
I'm afraid you'll be disappointed.
ฉันกลัวว่าคุณจะผิดหวัง
It's getting late.
มันเริ่มจะสายแล้ว
Please leave.
กรุณาออก.
Oh,
โอ้
don't forget what I just said.
อย่าลืมสิ่งที่ฉันเพิ่งพูดไป
If you change your mind someday,
ถ้าวันหนึ่งคุณเปลี่ยนใจ
you are welcome to come to me.
คุณยินดีที่จะมาหาฉัน
Come out.
ออกมา.
Dear.
ที่รัก.
I didn't realize my husband is such an expert at hiding.
ฉันไม่เข้าใจสามีของฉัน เป็นผู้เชี่ยวชาญในการซ่อนตัว
That was dangerous just now.
เมื่อกี้มันอันตราย
I had to protect your reputation.
ฉันต้องปกป้องชื่อเสียงของคุณ
Is it safe now?
ตอนนี้ปลอดภัยแล้วใช่ไหม?
Sure.
แน่นอน.
Thank you.
ขอบคุณ
If you don't come out, I'm going in.
ไม่ออกมาพี่จะเข้า
You're so careless.
คุณประมาทมาก
I thought you liked this kind of fun.
ฉันคิดว่าคุณชอบความสนุกสนานแบบนี้
Put me down.
วางฉันลง
Don't let it happen again.
อย่าให้มันเกิดขึ้นอีก
I'm afraid I might lose control and accidentally hurt you.
ฉันกลัวว่าฉันจะสูญเสียการควบคุม และทำร้ายคุณโดยไม่ตั้งใจ
Four hours, not a moment less.
สี่ชั่วโมง ไม่น้อยไปสักนิด
(If Gu Zhaoxi harbors ill intent, he's bound to leave traces.)
(หาก Gu Zhaoxi มีเจตนาร้าย เขาคงทิ้งร่องรอยไว้)
(If he intends to mimic me,)
(ถ้าเขาตั้งใจเลียนแบบผมนะ)
(is there proof of his gathering details about my habits and preferences)
(มีหลักฐานรายละเอียดการรวบรวมของเขาหรือไม่ เกี่ยวกับนิสัยและความชอบของฉัน)
(or a portrait of his true face?)
(หรือภาพใบหน้าที่แท้จริงของเขา?)
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪ต้นหลิวพลิ้วไหวในสายลมยามพลบค่ำ♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪ตรอกซอกซอยโบราณคอยรักษาความลับของกาลเวลา♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪หินบลูสโตนมีรอยประทับแห่งชีวิต♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪กลีบร่วงหล่น ความปรารถนาอันไม่สิ้นสุด♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪ความปรารถนายังคงอยู่ในใจฉัน♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪ สายพิณถอนใจ สำหรับการจากลาอันแสนเศร้า♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪เรื่องราวในอดีตฝังอยู่ในจิตวิญญาณของฉัน♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪ความรักยังคงอยู่ มิอาจลืมเลือน♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪ม้วนหนังสือที่เปื้อนหมึกหวนนึกถึงอดีต♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪แต่ละจังหวะมีความคิด♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪ความเจริญรุ่งเรืองจางหายไปเหมือนความฝัน♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪เรื่องราวในอดีตฝังอยู่ในจิตวิญญาณของฉัน♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪ความรักยังคงอยู่ มิอาจลืมเลือน♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪ม้วนหนังสือที่เปื้อนหมึกหวนคิดถึงอดีต♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪แต่ละจังหวะมีความคิด♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪ความเจริญรุ่งเรืองจางหายไปเหมือนความฝัน♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪ เรื่องราวในอดีตฝังอยู่ในจิตวิญญาณของฉัน ♪